Contact

661-713-6000 (Mobile)

www.linkedin.com/in/danita-daley (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Healthcare Management Nursing Hospitals

Certifications

Certified Professional in Utilization Review (CPUR)

American Nurses Association ~ Journey to Magnet Excellence/E

Nurse Executive, Advanced Certification

Registered Nurse – California, Texas, and Ohio

Hospital Accreditation Certified Professional (HACP) ~ Certified in the Joint Commission Accreditation

Dr. Danita Daley

VP and Chief Nursing Officer at RILEY CHILDREN'S HOSPITAL Greater Los Angeles Area

Summary

Accomplished nurse executive with more than 18 years of nursing leadership experience and proven skills in Transformational and Servant Leadership improving patient care delivery systems. Leadership experience managing multiple service lines. Certified in Joint Commission accreditation. A doctoral-prepared nursing executive who is uniquely qualified to lead by turning evidence into action, appreciating technology, understanding the importance of advocating for change, acknowledging the need for multidisciplinary care, and the advanced knowledge of nursing practice to represent and advance the nursing profession. Versatile, intuitive and forwardthinking visionary, healthcare leader equipped with leadership in overseeing organizational decision-making, strategic planning, performance improvement planning, and goal setting for the organization. Followed and adhered to the principles of The Professional Practice Model based on Maria O'Rourke's Role Based Practice Model supported by a shared-governance model of leadership. Dedicated and passionate team player with a talent for building and fostering cohesive teams. Build collaboration and teamwork through the fundamentals of compelling direction, stable structure, supportive context, and shared mindset. Effectively interact with medical staff to develop, nurture and manage relations that exemplify trust and collaboration.

Areas of Expertise:

- Strategic Leadership
 Patient Care
 Patient/Family Satisfaction
- Critical Care Services Case Management Clinical Best Practices
- Critical Care Planning Mgt
 Quality Improvement
 Change Management
- Operational Management
 Collective Bargaining Negotiation
 Budget Management
- Regulatory Compliance Nurse Management Cost Containment

Experience

RILEY CHILDREN'S HOSPITAL
VP and Chief Nursing Officer
June 2020 - Present (2 months)

Indianapolis, Indiana, United States

A-List Properties
Business Owner
January 2016 - Present (4 years 7 months)
Canton, Ohio Area

Family-owned real estate investors/operators who are focusing on reinvigorating the community through the purchase, renovation, and rental of single-family residences, commercial properties, land development, property management, and restaurant operations. Since 2016 we have been providing uncompromised customer services for our customers, renters, and community. Our staff includes renovation, leasing, and management professionals with a focus on quality.

Daley Consulting Services
Healthcare Executive Consultant
2016 - Present (4 years)
Greater Los Angeles Area

Assist hospitals and health care organizations determine administrative direction, planning and coordination of healthcare services. Develop a positive culture by changing behaviors, leading by example, talking purpose, training beyond the task, eliminating silos, staying focused to engage, and execute daily. Advise on cost-containment strategies to increase revenue through improved budgetary compliance. Collaborate with nursing and physician leadership to strategize and identify exemplary, cost effective clinical practices for implementation. Consult on practices to improve both employee engagement and patient satisfaction results.

Select 2016 Consultations, Training & Presentations:

- Developed and delivered dynamic and straightforward education and coaching for up to 40 participants related to patient satisfaction improvement plans. Researched organization history and trends. Created seminar and support materials. Developed plans for improvement and provided coaching and guidance.
- Developed and provided strategic plans for the leadership of 4 direct reports and oversight of inpatient nursing units and 5 primary care clinics.
 Developed strategic nursing plan. Conducted recruitment to fill open patient

care positions. Developed budget and cost-containment strategies and quality improvement plans.

UCSF Benioff Children's Hospital Oakland VP Operations, Chief Nursing Officer October 2019 - March 2020 (6 months) Oakland, CA

Prime Healthcare Administrator/Chief Nursing Officer 2018 - 2019 (1 year) San Dimas, California

Provides Chief Nursing Officer, Chief Operating Officer, and Risk Management duties, Effectively manages an award-winning community hospital in a Forprofit environment. The hospital is part of the Prime Healthcare System, one of the largest hospital systems in the country. SDCH has been recognized for receiving multiple awards, including: Healthgrades 2018 Patient Safety Award, 2018 Leapfrog Hospital Safety Grade "A" Award, Truven Health Analytics 100 Top Hospital Award, Truven Health Analytics 15 Top Health Systems Award for Outstanding Service in the Community, and Women's Choice Award for America's Best Hospitals for Patient Safety.

Henry Mayo Newhall Hospital Vice President and Chief Nursing Officer 2011 - 2017 (6 years) Valencia, CA

Accountable for administering hospital's nursing and patient services: planning, coordinating and directing all inpatient, emergency, surgical, perinatal, palliative, and outpatient services. Monitored quality and standards of patient care, patient safety, manages annual operating and capital budget, and regulatory compliance. Provided leadership for the planning and coordinating of all aspects of clinical nursing and patient care services. Directed and maintained a high consistency of care and positive organizational culture among nursing staff. Supported and facilitated an interdisciplinary delivery of patient care. The care included creating a healing environment in which collaboration is valued, and excellence in clinical care, education, and quality is promoted and achieved.

• Demonstrated success in accomplishing the emergency room transformation and improvement in Throughput efforts.

- Established care partnership model for patient care delivery where metrics showed significant improvements related to nursing-driven patient satisfaction scores
- Led in the several accreditations and certifications for the hospital, including Joint Commission Accredited Hospitals Organization Certification; Level II Trauma Center, as verified by the American College of Surgeons; Baby-Friendly designation from the World Health Organization and the United Nations Children's Fund and others.
- Served in a leading role and was instrumental in the hospital receiving several awards, including,

Advanced Primary Stroke Center awarded by the Joint Commission; American Heart/Stroke Association Get with the Guidelines Gold Plus Performance Achievement Award for Stroke; and Silver Medal of Honor awarded by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services in recognition of Organ Donation Rates.

Tulare Regional Medical Center Associate Chief Nursing Officer 2009 - 2011 (2 years)

Tulare, CA

Administered inpatient nursing units, including critical care services, step-down and telemetry services, emergency services, and heart catheterization laboratory. Guaranteed conformity of the entire operations with the State Title 22 and Nursing Practice Act compliance for nursing care. Managed approximately 400 FTEs. Ensured compliance with patient safety and accreditation regulatory bodies.

- Initiated the implementation of Siemens' Electronic Health Record in 2010.
- Reorganized the Emergency Department throughput model that generated \$75K monthly cost savings
- Set a record-breaking performance in hospital's history by executing the first productivity staffing model.
- Played an integral role in reducing the workforce from 24 down to 1 travel nursing staff thereby saving overtime dollars

Memorial Hermann Health System 2 years

System/Corporate Manager, Quality and Patient Safety 2008 - 2009 (1 year)

Houston, Texas Area

Leveraged industry expertise in managing quality, core measures, patient safety, and Joint Commission accreditation across system hospitals.

- Attained various awards from 2008 to 2009, including VHA Patient Safety Award, National Quality Forum Award, and Joint Commission Compliance Role Model Award
- Involved in the successful Joint Commission re-accreditations in 2008 and 2009.

Vice President, Quality and Ancillary Services 2007 - 2008 (1 year)

Beaumont/Port Arthur, Texas Area

Had full management accountability for quality, infection control, patient safety and advocacy, and Joint Commission accreditation. Provided strategic oversight to pharmacy, physical therapy, case management, social services, patient access, risk management, behavior health, and medical staff services. Provided exceptional patient care, thereby achieving the 2007 Press Ganey Compass Award.

 Earned recognition for the achievement of the Chest Pain Accreditation and Magnet Award Designation in 2007.

Shasta Regional Medical Center Director Case Management 2005 - 2007 (2 years) Redding, CA

Held primary accountability in designing the case management program.

Maintained active involvement in handling risk management, compliance, and

Joint Commission accreditation. Took charge of creating the avoidable day

tracking tool. Worked as hospitalist liaison, as well as prison liaison in 2006.

- Ensured accuracy in correcting the accommodation code errors that saved \$3K cost savings per mo.
- Obtained significant reduction of length of stay (LOS) from 62 to 46 which was considered as the lowest in the history of the organization.
- Established the Utilization Review and Denials committees.
- Developed the Hospitalists and Prison Program in 2006.

Doctors Hospital of Stark County Director of Quality and Case Management 2002 - 2005 (3 years)

Massillion, OH

Held full accountability in quality, case management, social services, patient advocacy, and infection control; while facilitating risk management,

compliance, nursing research, and Alpha Omega Academy (AOA) accreditation. Introduced various quality programs such as the Open Heart Quality Program in 2004.

- Decreased Actual Length of Stay (ALOS) from 5.67 to 4.44 days.
- Increased Core Measure compliance scores from 95% up to 100% of all indicators and Anthem Quality scores to 90%.
- Improved patient satisfaction scores to top 5 among 53 Triad hospitals.

Education

American Sentinel University

Doctorate of Nursing Practice DNP, Executive Leadership

Ashland University

Executive Master of Business Administration MBA, Business Administration and Management, General

Aultman College of Nursing and Health Sciences
Diploma in Registered Nursing, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse

Malone University

Bachelor of Science in Nursing BSN, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse